－ 漂亮
－ 别 别
￡- lt's nice, yeah.
￡- Yeah. No, no!
别碰, 胶水还没干
Don't touch it.
Glue's not dry yet.
－我为拍卖做的
－什么拍卖?
￡- l made it for the auction.
￡- What auction?
拍卖会啊 Ray
The auction, Ray.
上个月我一直在说的拍卖会
lt's all l've been talking
about for the past month.
我是Ally学校拍卖会的组织者之一
l'm on the organizing committee,
the auction for Ally's school
为操场建设筹集资金
for the playground
equipment￡-￡-
－ 拍卖会!
－ 我知道 我想起来了
￡- the auction!
￡- l know, l remember.
你为操场筹集资金的拍卖
The auction, you're on the committee
for the playground equipment.
你一直说的那个
That's all you've
been talking about￡-￡-
我还是听你唠叨的
l listen to you.
翻译: 柠檬蛋
F6 美剧总部
http://www.friends6.com/
打搅一下
Excu￡-￡- excuse me.
嗨 欢迎光临
Um, hi, welcome
圣母信念拍卖夜
to Our Lady of Faith's
Auction Night.
我是Debra Barone
l'm Debra Barone.
现场拍卖即将开始
We're gonna start the live auction
in a few minutes,
所以这是参加无声拍卖的最后机会了
so this is your last chance
to sign up for this silent one.
希望大家都玩的开心
And l hope everybody's
having a lot of fun.
谢谢
Thank you.
Frank, 你为竞价?
Frank, you're bidding
on the pedicure?
你参加这些竞价干吗?
Why are you signing up
for all these things?
别管我, 我在哄抬价格
Leave me alone,
l'm just trying to drive the prices up.
又想当大人物是不是
Just trying to be
a big shot.
你就不能参加点便宜的你又喜欢的?
Why don't you pick one little thing
that you really like￡-￡-
嗨! 无声拍卖
Hey, hey,
silent auction.
我做不了 我怎么就同意了呢
l can't do this.
Why did l let her talk me into this?
我不想站在一群人面前
l don't want to be
in front of people.
我不想当臭拍卖师
l don't wanna be
no stinking auctioneer.
那冰淇淋你吃不吃?
You gonna eat
that spumoni?
－ Ray 该你了
－ 听着, 算了吧
￡- Ray, it's time, come on.
￡- Listen, no￡-￡-
让Robert去吧 他又高声音又好
why doesn't Robert do it?
He's tall, got a good voice.
你来吧
￡- Yeah, they'd hear me.
￡- You should do it, you can talk￡-￡-
－ 说就行了
－ 嗨
￡- Yeah, just speak. Speak.
￡- Hi.
大家好 现场拍卖开始
Hi everybody, l guess it's time
for the live auction.
我叫Ray 主持拍卖的那个
l'm Ray.
l'm Ray the auction guy.
And, uh￡-￡-
谁要烤牛肉?
how about a hand
for the roast beef?
谁举手竞拍烤牛肉?
Let's hear it
for that roast beef.
我猜你们都是吃素的?
l guess what, are the rest
of you are veterinarians or something?
我指素食主义者
l mean vegetarians.
总之我们今天是为了孩子
Anyway, listen, we're here
for the kids because, uh,
为了孩子的明天
they're the future
and they deserve￡-￡-
他们应该有个操场玩耍
they deserves
a new playground, really.
可以滑坡,荡秋千
So that they can slide
and swing upside down
摔个跟头
and break their necks.
快开始
￡- Just start.
￡- Okay.
首先拍卖的是珠宝盒
Here we go, we're gonna start
with the￡-￡- with the jewelry box
- 你可以....
-放珠宝!
￡- where you, uh...
￡- Put your jewelry.
放珠宝进去
...put your jewelry
right in that.
低价以....
And we'll start
the bidding at, what?
- 20
- 美元?
￡- 20.
￡- Dollars?
对 20美元!
Yeah, $20.
$20
谁为这出20美元?
Who's gonna bid $20
for this fine piece of craftsmanship,
出自能工巧匠之手
finely crafted
by a fine craftsman...
碰巧我和她睡一屋
who l happen
to sleep with?
对不起 只要20
Sorry, uh￡-￡-
so, 20, that's all.
低价是$20
Let's start a bidding
at $20.
看看这精美的抽屉
lt's a fine piece.
Look at the fine drawers.
$20
$20, that's all we￡-￡-
$15
1 5.
$15怎么样?
How about $1 5?
Oops.
3块呢? 3块有人要吗?
Three?
Do l hear $3
出自能工巧匠
for this finely,
finely crafted
的一堆碎片
pile of rubble almost?
谁有带子, 有包装带就送他了
Who's got a bag?
lf you've got a bag, you can have it.
啊! 同情出价
Oh, mercy bid, right there.
Thank you.
谢谢你 Barone警官
Thank you,
Officer Barone.
你可以把小人国的犯人关这里
You can lock up
your tiny little prisoners in there,
虽然越狱是一点不难
although l think it's gonna be easy
for them to get out.
凡是我老婆碰的东西都会掉
Everything my wife
touches falls off,
你们可以想象我有多害怕
so you can guess
how scared l am.
嗨 小泥裤裤
Hey, puddlepants.
现在给泥马一只伴侣吧
Now, give Gumby
some Pokey.
哇
Whoa!
我不想说天气冷
l don't wanna say
that was cold,
但你嘴里开盏灯会冒气的
but if your mouth opened a little light
would come on.
我没心情做好不好
l'm just not really
in the mood, okay?
别这样
Come on.
What, not in the mood?
今晚很棒
Tonight was great.
孩子们有新操场我也拍到了高尔夫的东西
The kids got the new playground
and l got the golf thing,
你还带了个拍卖师回家
you got to go home
with the auctioneer.
谁没心情啊?
So who's in the mood?
Do l hear in the mood?
你就不怕我碰你 你那玩意掉下来?
Aren't you afraid
if l touch it, it'll fall off?
那是个好笑话
That was a good joke,
wasn't it?
别人问我是不是准备好的
People asked me
if l'd planned that, and l said,
我说我是灵机一动
"No, l just came up
with it like that."
你真是个喜剧"天才"
You're a brilliant
farceur.
好啦
Come on.
我知道你生笑话的气
l know, you're mad
at the jokes.
你就是停不下来 对不对
You just￡-￡- you just couldn't stop,
could you, Ray?
我把他们都搞定了嘛
l was killing them,
it was great.
那盒子撒架真是时候
That box falling apart,
that was the best thing
打破了现场尴尬的气氛
that could've happen.
That broke the ice.
你让我出丑了
You embarrassed me.
什么?没有
What? No!
lt was all fun.
我告诉你
Come on,
l told you,
别人以为我们故意的
people thought
that we did it on purpose.
我觉得丢脸
l felt humiliated.
别觉的丢脸
Don't feel
humiliated.
别教我怎么感觉
Don't tell me
how to feel.
你想错了嘛
But you're wrong.
这没什么对错 我就这么想了
There's no right or wrong,
this is how l feel.
你不能教我想丢不丢脸
我已经丢脸了
You can not tell me
not to be humiliated, l just am.
－ 好嘛, 就那么想嘛
－ 我现在不那么想了
￡- Okay, all right, feel humiliated.
￡- l don't anymore.
－ 好嘛
－ 我现在生气
￡- Okay, all right￡-￡-
￡- Now l'm just angry.
我不相信...
l mean, l can't believe￡-￡-
l can't believe
今晚你做的已经够出格了
you￡-￡- it's bad enough
what you did to me tonight,
你却一点悔意都没有
but you don't even care
how l feel about it.
你只关心你多么风光
你这个笑娼
All you care about is how well you did,
you laugh￡-whore.
你还是回到丢脸的阶段好
Maybe you should go back
to being humiliated.
别这样
Come on,
what do you￡-￡-
别那么小气嘛
don't be such
a bad sport.
你是我怎么样 你会怎么想
What if you were me?
What would you do?
我会跟着我丈夫的笑话笑
l would laugh
at all my husband's jokes,
脱掉衣服 嘿咻完了一起看电视
strip off my clothes, have my way
with him and then put on Tv.
做梦
Keep dreaming.
我会变得很淘气哦
l would￡-￡-
l'd be so naughty.
我还可能说黄话
l might even
talk dirty, oh!
想我想明白
So let me get
this straight.
今晚你做的你一点不在乎?
What you did to me tonight
wouldn't bother you?
在乎?高兴还来不及呢
Bother?
l would be flattered.
是吗?咱俩等着瞧
Oh yeah?
All right, we'll see.
什么?
What? What?
－ 你什么意思等着瞧
－ 没你事儿
￡- What do you mean, we'll see?
￡- None of your business.
你想报复还是怎么着
What are you gonna do,
try and get me or something?
这么说吧 你就等着"高兴"吧
Let's just say,
prepare to be flattered.
好啦
Come on.
You know, they say
俗话说夫妻上床不生气
couples shouldn't
go to bed angry.
我没生气啦 晚安
l'm not angry anymore.
Good night.
你没生气?我不相信
You're not angry anymore?
l might not believe you.
你得证明一下
You might have
to prove that.
我知道了你用不嘿咻惩罚我
l see. That's how you're gonna
get me, holding back sex?
真有想法
How original.
这就能报复我了?
You think
that's gonna get me?
我是做爱沙漠里的骆驼
l'm a sex camel.
不做爱 (我忍......)
Without sex.
骆驼? 这个笑话好
Sex camel.
That's a good one.
我得赶紧记下来
Sex camel.
l should write that one down.
尽情笑吧 小丑
Laugh it up,
funny man.
什么
Okay, what?
你以为我怕了?
You think
l'm scared now?
我才不怕呢 小妞
l'm not scared,
girlie.
我一点都不怕
You hear me?
l'm not scared.
一点都不怕
噢 妈妈咪呀
Ow, Mommy, ow.
－ 你没事吧？
－ 嗯
￡- Are you okay?
￡- Yeah, yeah.
只是暂时失下明
Just a little
temporary blindness.
听着Ray 我在想
Listen, Ray,
l was thinking
昨晚的拍卖会
about the auction
last night
和那些你说的笑话
and all the jokes
that you made
我太认真了
and you know,
l was taking myself too seriously.
你是对的 我跟你道歉
You were right, so,
l just want to apologize.
－ 真的?
－ 真的
￡- Really?
￡- Yeah.
事实上你是个好拍卖师
Because the fact is, you were
just a great auctioneer.
谢谢你
So, you know,
thank you.
你说要报复呢?
What about you saying
that you're gonna get me back?
那是气头上
That was just
in the heat of the moment.
我不会的
l'm not gonna get you.
－ 给我果汁
－ 该怎么说  Ally?
￡- l want juice.
￡- What do you say, Ally?
－ 请
－ 你要什么吗 Ray?
￡- Please.
￡- You want something, Ray?
请给我果汁
Juice is good.
Please.
只够给Ally了
There's really
only enough left for Ally.
要别的吗?汽水怎么样?
You want something else?
How about a soda?
－ 早餐喝汽水?
－ 没别的了
￡- Soda for breakfast?
￡- That's all we have.
拿着
￡- There.
￡- All right.
妈妈 请问我能喝汽水吗?
Mommy, may l have
a soda, please?
有礼貌才对Ally
That was a very nice way
to ask for it, Ally.
不行 亲爱的
No, honey.
等等
Wait a minute.
你摇过了
You shook this,
didn't you?
－ 没有
－ 早餐喝汽水
￡- What? No.
￡- Soda for breakfast.
你想喷我脸上
You want this
to explode in my face.
－ 我干嘛要怎么做?
－ 心知肚明
￡- Why would l want that?
￡- We all know why.
汽水喷我脸上
Soda in my face,
止痛剂涂在裤头上
Bengay in my shorts,
过期泻药藏蛋糕里
Ex￡-Lax in the brownies.
我也夏令营过
l went to camp.
我不报复你
l'm not gonna
get you, Ray.
葡萄呢？
How about the grapefruit?
你以为我挤葡萄在你眼里？
You think l rigged a grapefruit
to squirt in your eye?
你口气没否认
Doesn't really sound
like a denial.
我告诉你我没有
l'm telling you,
l'm not￡-￡-
我知道你这么说
l know you're telling me
you're not,
接着我会相信
so l will think
you'll not.
但我可没那么笨
But l am not
that big an idiot.
Ray, 喝你的汽水 不会有事的
Ray, nothing's going to happen.
So just drink your soda.
－ 你来喝
－我不想喝
￡- You drink it.
￡- l don't want it.
哈！
Ah, yeah!
那我给Ally咯？
How about￡-￡-
l'll give it to Ally.
我不想孩子早餐喝汽水
l don't want her
having soda for breakfast.
－ 帮我打开总行吧
－ 好吧
￡- Just to open it for me.
￡- Okay, go. Fine.
你真让这事情发生？
Yeah, you would do that.
You would let it explode
喷在孩子脸上？你的亲身骨肉
in your own daughter's face,
your own flesh and blood.
继续
Go ahead.
你什么母亲啊？
What kind of mother
are you?
当你关进疯人院的时候
The kind of mother who's
gonna be awarded custody
荣获最佳监护奖的母亲
when they take you
to the booby hatch.
Ally 亲爱的去换衣服
Ally, go get dressed,
honey.
Debra 你玩什么把戏
Debra, what kind of
con game are you running?
是你的错 Frank
lt's your
own fault, Frank.
谁教你全部拍下来
Who told you to sign up
for all those things?
我没想到拍下垃圾回家
l didn't expect
to win this crap.
不是垃圾
￡- lt's not crap.
￡- Oh yeah?
80美元的独木舟
$80 for the use
of a canoe.
这是漂流垃圾
That is floating crap.
别人觉的划舟是件浪漫事
Some people would consider
a canoe ride romantic.
你没见过船翻
Guess you didn't see
"Deliverance."
Ray你还喝不喝的
￡- Ray, you gonna drink this or what?
￡- Okay.
你有观众了是不
You got your audience
now, right?
我一开大家都笑我是不是
Everybody's here, l open the￡-￡-
yeah, big laugh on Raymond.
爸 别开
Dad, Dad, no!
你发什么神经
What's your problem?
瞧 我说不捉弄你吧
See, l told you.
当然 当然
Yeah, you did.
Of course.
你不会拿汽水报复的
Of course, why would you
settle for soda?
我自己都每天喷在脸上
That's not satisfying. You see me
spill soda on myself every day.
你要报复更厉害的对不?
lt's gonna be much bigger
than soda, isn't it?
我的车 我的工作
My car, my job,
或是我最敏感的部位
my most intimate
of areas.
我警惕着呢
l'm watching you.
我警惕.........
l'm watch￡-￡-
好我会转达的 再见
Okay. l'll give him the message.
Yeah. Bye￡-bye.
－ 嗨 亲爱的
－ 嗨
￡- Hi, honey.
￡- Hi.
刚才克拉伦斯来电话
That was Clarence, the guy
who's coordinating
－ 负责名人高尔夫的人
－ 怎么了?
￡- your celebrity golf thing.
￡- Oh yeah?
他说你以后从西边的门进俱乐部
He said you should use
the west entrance of the country club.
西边的门 知道了
West entrance.
Okay, got it.
带橡胶鞋别带金属的鞋
And bring your rubber spikes
instead of the metal ones.
真的? 好
Really? Thanks.
看到没?她不怀好意
You see that?
She's evil.
－ 什么?
－我告诉过你,她要报复我
￡- What?
￡- l told you. lt's bigger than soda.
她想我在高尔夫混合赛上出丑
That's where it's all
going down, at the Pro￡-Am.
－ 你说她要报复你
－闭嘴!
￡- You mean where she gonna get you?
￡- Shut up.
当然是了
Yes, of course,
it's perfect.
她总是嫉妒我玩高尔夫
She's always been
jealous of my golf.
她知道我花了多少时间和金钱在上面
She knows how much l love it and how
much time and money l spend on it.
她想让我和高尔夫一起出丑
She wants to humiliate
me with my mistress.
我了解她
l know her.
我是她肚里的蛔虫
l am hip to her jive.
但她也是我肚里的蛔虫
But she's hip to me too.
So that's why￡-￡-
你得帮我侦查清楚
listen, you got to go in there
and find out what she's up to.
－ 什么?
－ 做条子审讯做的事
￡- How?
￡- Do what cops do.
我不知道, 把真相揪出来
l don't know,
just get the truth.
在她摆律师牌前开她的口
Make her talk
before she lawyers up.
快嘛 用台灯射她脸什么的
Come on, l don't know,
use the big light.
你神经病啊
What are you, loopy?
她是你老婆 她不会出你的丑的
She's your wife,
she's not gonna humiliate you.
我没时间告诉你婚姻是什么
l don't have time
to explain marriage to you.
你做就是了
Please, come on,
just go do it.
Debra喝的
Debra's soda, okay.
你要报复Raymond?
Are you gonna get
Raymond?
不会
No.
－ 怎么样 怎么样?
－ 她不报复你
￡- What, what, what?
￡- She's not gonna get you.
－ 你怎么知道
－ 我问她
￡- How do you know?
￡- 'Cause l said to her
你要报复Raymond?
她说不会. 结案了
are you gonna get Raymond?
She said no. Case closed.
－ 就这样?
－ 她还说双胞胎不是你的
￡- That's it?
￡- She also said the twins aren't yours.
Come on.
倒底怎么样?
Really,
what's going on?
我知道心怀鬼胎的人
l know when people
are up to something.
－ 我可以闻出来
－ 她闻的正常?
￡- l can smell it.
￡- And she smells all right?
她很正常
She smells very good.
天啊 她收买你了!
Oh my God, she got to you,
didn't she?
－ 你成帮凶了
－ 别说胡话
￡- You're both in on it.
￡- You're talking crazy.
－ 你当然愿意帮她了
－什么
￡- Sure, you'd love to get me too, huh?
￡- What?
你也想我出丑
You'd love
to see me humiliated.
不是吗?哥?
lsn't that right,
my brother?
Raymond Raymond
Raymond
Raymond, Raymond,
Raymond.
好
All right.
醒醒!
Wake up, wake up.
怎么了?
What?
What's wrong?
告诉你我取消了
Just so you know,
l canceled it.
－ 取消什么了?
－ 高尔夫比赛
￡- What? Canceled what?
￡- The golf outing.
－ 我退出了
－ 为什么?
￡- Backed out.
￡- What? Why?
为什么?因为你闻起来不对
甜心
Why? Because you smell,
sweetheart.
天啊 我得离你远点
Oh my God,
l have to leave you.
这就是为什么你那么做
No, no. That's where
you're gonna do it.
我知道你设下圈套的方式
我知道你怎么想
That's where you're gonna set
your trap. l know how your mind works.
你自己想什么都不知道
You don't even know
how your mind works.
我不会报复你
l'm not going to get you.
你就做了吧
Will you just do it?
All right, come on!
不管你怎么报复, 现在就做吧
Whatever you're gonna do,
just do it now,
因为我再也无法忍受了
'cause l can't
take it anymore.
你真担心啊
You're really
worried about this.
－我不是担心我是焦虑
－ 那你焦虑了是不是
￡- l'm not worried, l'm anxious.
￡- So you're feeling anxious?
－我是焦虑
－ 别那样
￡- l'm feeling anxious.
￡- You shouldn't.
－ 什么?
－别那样想
￡- What?
￡- Don't feel that way.
别教我怎么感觉
Don't tell me
how to feel!
这就是行了
And there it is.
什么?
Huh?
我把我的感觉给你了
l'll just give you a moment
to put it together.
拍卖会以后, Ray
After the auction, Ray,
当我感觉尴尬丢脸时候
when l was feeling
embarrassed and humiliated,
你不就告诉我同样的话吗?
didn't you say
the same thing to me?
－"别那么想"记得吗?
－我记得
￡- "Don't feel that way." Remember that?
￡- l do remember that.
你开始折磨我的时候
Because that's when
you started torturing me.
噢
Oh, oh￡-￡-
其实你没做什么?
So you didn't do
anything?
你让我自讨苦吃?
You let me do this
to myself?
一直以来我可以喝那汽水的
All week long
l could have had soda?
我可以吃蛋糕的
l could have had
brownies?
我可以穿着内裤的
l could have worn
underwear?
全是我的错?
So it was all me?
这就是你报复我的办法
That's how you got me?
没有什么方法
Nothing l could think
of could screw you up more
可以让你自己折磨自己更好的了
than what's already
in that beautiful mind.
晚安 Ray
Good night, Ray.
对啊 心在作怪
That's right,
beautiful mind.
现在心决定
'Cause it takes
a beautiful mind to come up
不取消参加高尔夫了
with not canceling
the golf outing,
告诉你不去
but telling you
that l did
其实是骗你说真话的
just to get you
to spill your guts.
聪明的人不止你一个
Okay? You're not
the only clever one.
青出于蓝胜于蓝
You zig, l zag.
－ 你真取消了对吧?
－ 是的!
￡- You canceled it, didn't you?
￡- Yes!
看见没Frank?
没蚊子
You see, Frank?
No mosquitoes.
真好啊
Oh, this is lovely.
我很高兴我们拍到了
l'm so glad
we won this.
你总对好东西不感冒
You're always against
anything good.
只要是我喜欢的
Anything l might like.
这太花钱了
lt costs too much money.
你就不能
Just have to￡-￡-
享受下生活?
why can't you
just enjoy life?
哦起航了
Oh, here we go!
Frank! Frank!
Frank!
你做什么? 船上没桨!
What are you doing?
l don't have the paddles!
Frank!
天啊 Frank!
Oh, Frank!